Mohammad R. Tayyebi

tayyebimohammadreza@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/mohammadrezatayyebi | github.com/tayyebi

Summary

Software Engineer with 5^+ years of experience mainly focused on back-end development and business analysis. Competitive programmer, skilled with database design and server maintenance, exact in tracking and tracing projects, skilled with reporting, comfortable in collaboration with internal and external stakeholders, always ready for challenges, active learner.

EXPERIENCE

Software Developer

Freelancer and Independent Contractor

2017 - Present

- Served 50⁺ legal and individual customers covering various custom software design needs from interface design to BI reporting.
- Developed 3 IoT and Sensors Network projects back-end and sockets in collaboration with electronics and robotics engineers.
- Developed 15^+ desktop and 30^+ web applications.
- Recommended by 10^+ customers and managers.

IT Consultant and Web Developer

Part-time Remote • Maharashtra, India

June 2022 - Present

Universal Versatile Society

- Digitally transformed the business by providing a multi-vendor marketplace with the least time and cost which became possible by customization of the WordPress/WooCommerce.
- Configured Docker and containerized the solution on the DigitalOcean which benefits the organization with scale profit by maximizing usage of the cloud machine's available resources.
- Reorganized project architecture to maximize alignment of project code structure with work break structures. It saved 2 weeks of training time for each new volunteer and near to 1 out of 6 hours a day in task clearance because of the clean and direct assignment of tasks to the equivalent file in the code repository.
- Co-lead, interviewed and trained a team of 12 volunteer programmers and content developers with high diversity in case of time-zone, nationality, and proficiency level. Currently supporting the team with required training.

Instructor

Guest Teacher • Hamedan, Persia

Bu-Ali Sina University

2018 - 2020

- Was instructor of Full-stack developer workshop at Scientific Society of Computer Science and Engineering.
- Taught Advanced MVC Design Pattern crash course at Scientific Society of Computer Science and Engineering.

Full-stack Developer

Tokan Tav Tejarat

Full-time on-site • Hamedan, Persia

June 2022 – December 2022

• Established a clean code-base of an online marketplace based on Laravel to handle the company's 3⁺ years strategic plan of growth and development. Designed database and implemented APIs with the approach to achieve the most possible scalability of the business by accepting wide diversity of products and services to be traded online.

• Launched required infrastructure for production and development containing GIT, CDN, SMTP, KMS, workflow, FTP, monitoring, and database servers to automate and optimize the company's workflow.

SKILLS, PROJECTS, AND TECHNOLOGIES

PHP and MySQL: PHP 8 with Laravel, PHP 5

C# and SQL Server: ASP.NET Core 3, WCF with Xamarin, Windows Forms Application with EntityFramework 6, WPF with SQLite 3, ASP.NET MVC 2 with jQuery, ASP.NET Web Forms 4.0 with Ajax, ASP.NET Web Forms 2.0 Other Languages: Java (Android), Python with TensorFlow, C++ 14 (Android), C++ 11, JavaScript, PineScript v5, Google Apps Script

Server Administration: Windows Server, Debian/Ubuntu Linux, Docker Soft Skills and Project Management: SWOT Analysis, BA, UML

Book | Department of Information Technology and other magics

Open-source

CERTIFICATIONS

Data Analytics: Foundations | NASBA – LinkedIn Learning; 2023.
 Business Process Modeling | PMI – LinkedIn Learning; 2023.
 Business Analysis Foundations | IIBA – LinkedIn Learning; 2023.
 Certified Instructor | TVTO; 2015.

Enterprise Web Development with ASP.NET | TVTO; 2013.

ID ARJJpf3C_YEzxZBHzfKYZC0ItgT0 ID AfYAsNtoeNfnZLlUaZbuEe8pVAoc ID ASh_GL8boaVrpqKcmoJn2Wna8YEt Contract No. 5243 96/30_475616/2 No. 90163030986

• Abu-Dhabi, United Arab Emirates

Honors and Awards

WorldSkills 2017 | Champion, National Gold Medalist

- IT Software Solutions for Business
- 4 days of web, desktop, and mobile programming, data architecture, and software analysis in competition with tens of talented youth from different countries.

Khwarizmi Youth Award 2015 | National Ranked 3rd

• Tehran, Persia

- Computer Science
- Implemented a centralized authentication and authorization system.
- Interdisciplinary placed among the top 45 selected students out of 25339 and awarded in the most creditable scientific festival of Persia, even before attending university.

EDUCATION

Khaje Nasir Toosi University of Technology

Master of Business Administration, Minor in Marketing Management

Bu-Ali Sina University

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering, Minor in Information Technology

• Tehran, Persia September 2021 – May 2023

• Hamedan, Persia September 2016 – August 2020